Travis Carlson

Full Stack Developer



Full Stack Java Developer at Goldblatt Systems, Tucson AZ

October 2012 - October 2023



EHR Design and Maintenance

Significant contributions included designing a converter library for minimal transfer of data between client and server, implementing client-side routing for cross-modular compatibility, and optimizing the clinical documentation user experience by prioritizing and batching asynchronous service calls. Eventually became the go-to expert for Physician Portal infrastructure.

Technologies: Eclipse, Java GWT (GXT), JSNI, REST, JSON, Javascript, JQuery, CSS, Freemarker, Keycloak OAuth



ORM Specialist

ONC requirements necessitated a complete redesign of the Care Plans schema. This involved updated entity mappings, table design, and data conversion in rerunnable versioned deployments. These changes paved the way for ORM enhancements in other domains such as patient scheduling, questionnaire ingestion, and preferencing.

Technologies: Spring JPA (Hibernate ORM), SQL (Oracle) Queries/Views, DDL, Stored Procedures, Spring Security, Spring AOP, Dependency Injection



Force Multiplier

Cultivated a strong cross-disciplinary rapport with developers, DBAs, and QA to continuously improve product functionality and performance. Whenever critical customer issues arose, communicated directly with the implementation team to swiftly deploy hotfixes and patches. Consistently prioritized the productivity of all team members.

Technologies: JIRA (Confluence), UML, Balsalmiq, Microsoft Teams, JUnit, Log4j, Bash, Git, Maven, Jenkins, Tomcat

Previous Industry Experience

Android Developer at Yellow Brick Code, Tucson AZ

June 2011 - February 2012

Prototyped Android application interfacing to customers' web sites

Intern at ScriptSave Corporation, Tucson, AZ

may 2010 - July 2010

Overhauled an asset audit system using Microsoft Access, InfoPath, and Powershell

Coop Software Engineer at IBM, Tucson, AZ

Summer 2005 and Fall 2007

Tape controller maintenance and software installation



Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Minor in Mathematics

Computer Engineering coursework



Self Education

The Complete React Developer Course (w/ Hooks and Redux)

Udemy, In Progress

Complete C# Unity Developer 3D - Learn to Code Making Games Udemy, 2018

Creative Programming for Digital Media & Mobile Apps Coursera, 2013

Introduction to Databases Stanford Class2Go, 2013